<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<airline>
  <profile name="Braniff International Airways" iata="BN" color="Blue" country="122" CEO="Paul Revere Braniff " mentality="Aggressive" market="Global" preferedairport="DAL">
    <narrative narrative="Braniff International was founded in 1930 by insurance magnate Thomas Elmer Braniff and his brother Paul Revere Braniff. Two years before they had founed Tulsa-Oklahoma City Airline and served the route between these two Oklahoma cities in a 5 seat Stinson. A new airline was then founded by them and named Braniff Airways but was essentially the same as the airline before it, it served the same route with the additon of Wichita Falls,Texas. They were awarded the Chicago-Dallas airmail route by the USPS in 1935, and were the first airline to fly from Chicago to the U.S-Mexican border. In 1935 they bought Long and Harmon Airlines based at Fort Worth,TX and expanded its midwest routes. In 1943 Thomas Braniff started Aerovias Braniff to serve Mexico. During WW2 they leased aircraft to the military and let them use their Dallas Love Field facilities for pilot training and mechanics. After WW2 the CAB awarded them routes to the Caribbean,Central and South America. 1952 saw them buying Mid-Continent Airlines further expanding their presence in the mid west and into the South. In 1967 they bought Panagra, the alliance of Pan Am and Grace Airways, from the shareholders of those two companies, giving them even more South American routes. 1982 saw thier demise after fuel prices started hurting them and poor decisions after the airline industry deregulation of 1980, and other factors including low-load factors on the 747's, failed routes from new hubs, high interest rates, and a recession. At their end they had 82 planes, many 747's, DC-8's, and they even flew a Concorde owned by Air France and British Airways on the Dallas-Washington DC route under their own name. They at the end had 54 destinations around the world. Two failed attempts to bring them back include an airline named Braniff between 1983 and 1989 owned by hotel giant Hyatt using some of the former airlines assests and another from 1991 to 1992." /></profile>
  <info real="True" from="1928" to="1982" />
</airline>