<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<airline>
  <profile name="Eastern Air Lines" iata="EA" logo="EA" color="Purple" country="122" CEO="Eddie Rickenbacker" mentality="Aggressive" market="Global" preferedairport="MIA">
    <narrative narrative=" Eastern Air Lines was a composite of assorted air travel corporations, including Florida Airways and Pitcairn Aviation. In the late 1920s, Pitcairn Aviation won a contract to fly mail between New York City and Atlanta, Georgia on Mailwing single-engine aircraft. In 1929, Clement Keys, the owner of North American Aviation, purchased Pitcairn. In 1930, Keys changed the company's name to Eastern Air Transport. After being purchased by General Motors and experiencing a change in leadership after the Airmail Act of 1934, the airline became known as Eastern Air Lines.Eastern was one of the 'Big Four' domestic airlines created by the Spoils Conferences of 1930, and was headed by World War I flying ace Eddie Rickenbacker in its early years. It had a near monopoly in air travel between New York and Florida from the 1930s until the 1950s and dominated this market for decades afterward. Labor disputes and high debt loads strained the company in the late 1970s and early 1980s under the leadership of former astronaut Frank Borman. Frank Lorenzo acquired Eastern in 1985 and moved many of its assets to his other airlines, including Continental Airlines and Texas Air. After continued labor disputes and a crippling strike in 1989, Eastern ran out of money and was liquidated in 1991. American Airlines obtained many of Eastern's routes from Miami to Latin America and the Caribbean, while Delta Air Lines, Eastern's main competitor at Hartsfield Airport in Atlanta, acquired many of Eastern's Lockheed L-1011 aircraft. It served 140 destinations including many in South America they took over from Braniff in the 80s. Their fleet had 304 planes. Thier rich histroy can't all fir in this description and the stuff descibed is just a small part of thier history.   " /></profile>
  <info real="True" from="1926" to="1991" />
</airline>