<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<airline>
  <profile name="Empire Airlines" iata="EM" color="BlueViolet" country="122" CEO="Fred Johnson" mentality="Aggressive" market="Regional" preferedairport="GEG"  routefocus="Mixed" >
    <narrative
      narrative="Empire Airlines is a cargo and passenger airline with it's hub at Spokane,Washington. It's corporate headquarters are about 35 miles to the east of Spokane in Hayden,Idaho near Coeur d'Alene. It also calls the airport near Hayden home, Coeur d'Alene Pappy Boyington Field. It was founded in 1977 as Clearwater Flying Service in Orofino,Idaho. They did fire patrol,transporting outfitters into the backcountry,air ambulance,charters,flight instruction and even air pollution monitering. They purchased West Aire in 1980 and moved their HQ to where it is now. In 1981 they bought Executive Aviation of Missoula,Montana and leased some Twin Otters for US Forest Service Smoke Jumping contracts. In 1984 they were awarded contracts to transport people and goods into and out of the war torn Caribbean island of Grenada. They also started passenger service between Couer d'Alene and Boise and used Metro Liners. In 1988 they got a contract from FedEx which is still going on today, most of their fleet is painted in FedEx livery. They were to be the Spokane and Portland and later Seattle sector of the Cessna 208 cargo operation for FedEx. In 1989 they bought Pacific Alaska and two F27's. Between October 1993 and May 1994 they flew F27's in Hawaii for Mahalo Air who had to wait for their own planes. In 1995 they ended passenger service to focus on cargo. However in 2012 they would agree to operate two of their ATR 42-500's for Hawaiian under the name 'Ohana doing inter island flights, this started in March 2014. As of 2007 they had 33 Cessna 208B's and 13 ATR's of various kinds, 10 of them being 42's and 3 42's. They serve 18 states and Vancouver,Canada. Most of their destinations are in Washington and Oregon, but they have destinations in the southwest US too with focus cities at Forth Worth,Phoenix and Albuquerque and go up to Alaska too." />
  </profile>
  <info real="True" from="1977" to="2199"></info>
  <prefereds aircrafts="Cessna 208B Super Cargomaster,ATR 42-300,ATR 42-500,ATR 72-200,Fokker F27,Short 360,Fairchild Swearingen Metroliner"></prefereds>
  <!--the airliners the airline would start with which isn't on a route earyl (1988) late (2016)-->
    <airliners>
      <airliner type="Cessna 208B Super Cargomaster" early="15" late="33"></airliner>
      <airliner type="ATR 42-500" early="0" late="3"></airliner>
      <airliner type="ATR 42-300" early="0" late="7"></airliner>
      <airliner type="ATR 72-200" early="0" late="3"></airliner>
      </airliners>
 

</airline>